Guide to the Samuel A. Elliot collection,1927-1935.
Elliot, Samuel A. collection
- Series III. American Indian Defense Association, Inc. papers
  - The immediate tasks of the American Indian Defense Association, Inc.., December 10, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-6)
  - The Congressman Cramton mystery a partial explanation of his Flathead power site conduct., February 20, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Continued hunger and distress for Indian boarding school children., February 26, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Dr. Haven Emerson asks President Hoover to renew his plea for food and clothing for Indian children. February 28, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The war department set up of Flathead power rentals., February 28, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Hoover's emergency relief request for Indian children and what happened to it?, March 4, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Shall the Indian children's hopes, wakened by President Hoover, be dashed., March 6, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Petition to U.S. Senate to amend the deficiency bill., March 10, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The effect of the appropriations just recommended by the Senate Appropriations Committee., March 11, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The Interior Department's construction of the middle Rio Grande Conservancy contract is right., March 14, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The Senate should reconsider its acceptance of the conferee's report on the Indian food and items in the deficiency bill March 18, 1930. (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - To the officers of the Pueblos: the Swing-Johnson Indian., March 22, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Exactly what the Hoover food and standard for Indian boarding school children requires in the 1931 Interior Appropriation., March 22, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The record and position of the Indian Bureau, showing that the Indian children must rely on the Senate and their unofficial friends., March 22, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Mr. Walter H. Wheeler's charge against assistant Commissioner Scattergood of the Indian Bureau., March 24, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Part of the testimony of John Collier on the Flathead power site controversy., March 25, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Investigating Indian irrigation and reimbursable indebtedness., March 27, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The Flathead rental set up of the War Department, and its fictitious data obtained from what mysterious agency?, March 27, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The Flathead jugglery of the War Department, and its fictitious data obtained from some other agency., March 28, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - To the officers of the middle Rio Grande Pueblos: concerning how much money should be paid by the government to Conservancy District., March 31, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The power site decision at verge of injury to the and the Indians., April 4, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The new power proposal of the Department of the Interior., April 10, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Report on the food and clothing appropriation for Indian children., April 10, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Worse and worse grow the revealed intentions of the government departments with respect to the Flathead power site., April 11, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Luxuries for the Indian! "Slow starvation.", April 15, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Compares Flathead power site deal to Albert B. Fall record., April 21, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Subsidizing the Anaconda Copper Company in Montana., April 22, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Defeat this Indian Bureau Bill establishing tyranny over the Indians!, April 25, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - A new espionage over Indians proposed by the new Indian commissioners., April 29, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Copy of the letter addressed by the Board of Directors of the American Indian Defense Association, Inc., to Secretary Ray Lyman Wilbur of the Department of the Interior., May 6, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Editorial page 310, The New Republic, May 7, 1930. "Flogging of Indian children in government boarding schools." (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - I. Secretary Wilbur's reply to the Board of Director's letter., May 7, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - II. A letter by the Executive Secretary to the President of the Association dealing with Secretary Wilbur's letter., May 7, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - I. A letter by Dr. Haven Emerson to Secretary Wilbur., May 7, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - II. A letter by the Board of Directors to Secretary Wilbur., May 9, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Cramton and the power trust steal a march on Congress., May 9, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The Flathead license outrage and the Interior Department's ironical defense., May 20, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The Flathead license subverts the federal water power act and destroys public regulation., May 31, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Letter to the officers of the New Mexico Pueblos concerning Bill H.R. 12615., June 3, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The betrayal of regulation through the Flathead power site license., June 4, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Declares Simms Bill a threat to Pueblo Indian life., June 8, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - Letter from Secretary of the Interior Wilbur in regards to Flathead Power site., June 12, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The birthright of regulation sold, and the mess of pottage not secured in exchange by the unprecedented Flathead power license., June 18, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 9165-7)
  - The Indian Bureau when defying parental wishes and forcing Indian children into boarding schools., Undated 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-8)
  - Senator Frazier, Committee Chairman, moves to protect Pueblo Indians and white settlers of New Mexico (2 copies)., January 24, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-8)
  - Representative passes out March 2nd. Thereafter, the Swing-Johnson Bill can certainly be enacted., January 28, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-8)
  - The case against Herbert J. Hagerman of the Indian Bureau as established to date., February 5, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-8)
  - Indian education after two years, the situation demands action, not delay through a $100,000 self-investigation by the delinquent Indian Bureau., February 25, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-8)
  - The Indian Bureau charged with deception or with being the victim of deception in the matter of Navajo land adjustments., February 25, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-8)
  - Dr. Hoffman insists: "All that can reasonably be done is being done to promote the of our Indians." Is it true? A statistician's three horned dilemma., November 10, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-8)
  - Report on El Capitan Grande Indian and the Barona Ranch situation., November 14, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-8)
  - Report on El Capitan Grande Indian and the Barona Ranch situation., November 14, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Destruction of Indian rights and protections by the new grazing permit regulations of the Indian Bureau., January 22, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Improper guardianship., February 3, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Illegal and coercive leasing of Indian lands to whites through the Indian Bureau's permit scheme., February 5, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Letter to the officers of the Pueblos concerning the Compensation Bill., February 6, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Nothing but instantaneous action can save the economic life of the Navajos., February 9, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Can anything force the Indian Bureau to adequate action in the Navajo relief matter?, February 12, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Letter to all friends of the Navajo Indians concerning procrastination of Indian Office in responding to sheep crisis., February 14, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Increasing ruin of the Navajo tribe through government neglect following the storm disaster (2 copies)., February 19, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - "The apex of meanness" the Mescalero expenditures., February 20, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - To the members of congress and to friends of the Indian everywhere, letter signed by Indian leaders charging deplorable conditions of Indians., February 26, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Highlights of the case for removing H.J. Hagerman from the government payroll., February 29, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Resolution calling for government aid for Indians in distress and for the saving of the Navajo sheep. House Committee Resolution., March 2, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Open letter concerning forthcoming statement to be introduced into the Congressional record., March 8, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Memorandum for the Press, Secretary Wilbur's response to Senator King's statement in the Senate., March 9, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Statement by John Collier in reply to a statement by Secretary Ray Lyman Wilbur of the Interior Department. (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Pueblo council challenges Wilbur to prove statements., March 10, 1932; March 15, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Editorial. Albuquerque Journal. March 17, 1932, "Mr. Hagerman's salary." (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Editorial. New Mexico State Tribune. March 18, 1932, "The Hagerman Ouster." (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Editorial. Albuquerque Journal March 18, 1932, Secretary Wilbur's insulting letter to Isleta Pueblo Council. (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - "Indian Truth"? Controversy between the Indian Rights Association and the American Indian Defense Association., March 24, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Do you know? statistics on Indian Bureau expenditures., March 31, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Give and take between the Secretary of the Interior and the Indian tribes., April 6, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - More light on the Yakima Water Rights Bill., April 7, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Cause of the delay of the Pueblo Bill., April 14, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Press release declaring Bill H.R. 10351 a menace to all Indian tribes., April 22, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Proposed repeal of espionage and marital law statutes affecting Indians., April 26, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - A bill to gag and terrorize the employees of executive departments., May 6, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - International Committee on the graphic display of the Native Races of America., May 17, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Needs in administration of Indian property., May 20, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Letter to Commissioner of Indian Affairs protesting the proposed alienation of thirteen reservoir sites and Mountain Lakes, property of the Flathead tribe of Montana., May 28, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Shall the Hagerman Agreement divesting the Walapai tribe of Arizona be confirmed., May 30, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - The Walapai issue stated in a nutshell., June 8, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-9)
  - Why constructive Indian legislation is not being passed., June 2, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-10)
  - American Indian Defense Association Inc.., October 28, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 9165-10)
  - A statement about the Albuquerque Indian Boarding School under superintendent Reuben Perry who is now a candidate for assistant commissioner of Indian Affairs., January 20, 1933 (Box 46, Folder 9165-11)
  - Immediate tasks and events in Indian defense., January 21, 1933 (Box 46, Folder 9165-11)
  - The destruction of Indian tribal capital by the Indian Bureau in the year 1932., February 13, 1933 (Box 46, Folder 9165-11)
  - Information bulletin: of interest to the Pueblos, the Navajos and the allotted Indians., February 16, 1933 (Box 46, Folder 9165-11)
  - Wheeler-Howard appropriations total over six million dollars., February 1, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - House Committee ignores demand for Collier's removal., February 7, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - Important arts and crafts bill gets Senate Committee's approval., March 18, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - The Federal Government cannot evade its obligation to help the public school districts meet the costs of educating Indian youth., March 26, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - Senate Indian Committee opens public hearings on Oklahoma Welfare bill., April 8, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - Senate Committee concludes hearings on Oklahoma Welfare Bill---Grady Lewis presents moving plea for five tribes---Joseph Briner is lone dissenter., April 11, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - House Indian Committee opens public hearings on Thomas Rogers Bill-Creeks and Choctaws and Chickasaws submit endorsement., April 22, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - Suggested amendments to the Thomas-Rogers Bill., April 23, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - Issue of recovering federal jurisdiction over Five Civilized Tribes emerges as contested point at second hearing on Thomas-Rogers Bill., April 24, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - State courts defended by Eufaula Guardian at third hearing on Thomas-Rogers Bill-Grady Lewis presents cases to support charges., April 25, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - Clark Nicholas concludes testimony on Thomas-Rogers Bill-attacks argument of Grady Lewis., April 26, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - A 'dirt farmer" views the Oklahoma Indian problem extracts from letters of a white neighbor of the Cherokees which abound in great common sense., May 15, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - Some more common sense from an Oklahoma farmer this time anent the abolition of the Indian Bureau and the campaign against the Thomas-Rogers Bill., May 25, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - The company is fighting the arts and crafts bill., May 28, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - House Indian Committee bills Oklahoma Welfare Bill without discussion. Hopes now center on Senator Thomas to secure passage of Senate bill., May 29, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)
  - Bill to give tribes participating control over tribal funds is introduced., June 1, 1935 (Box 46, Folder 9165-12)